<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Web Design Telford | Web Design Shropshire</title>
	<atom:link href="https://www.yellowmarshmallow.co.uk/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://www.yellowmarshmallow.co.uk</link>
	<description>Web Design Company in Telford, Shropshire</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Wed, 12 Jun 2019 09:22:32 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=4.9.8</generator>
	<item>
		<title>3 hottest trends in web design and branding</title>
		<link>https://www.yellowmarshmallow.co.uk/blog/3-hottest-trends-in-web-design-and-branding/</link>
		<pubDate>Wed, 12 Jun 2019 09:22:32 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Lee Stewart]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Blog]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.yellowmarshmallow.co.uk/blog/3-hottest-trends-in-web-design-and-branding/</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<p>Over the years, web design has changed a lot. Early websites from the 90s now look like relics from a lost civilisation. There are many reasons for the change in<span class="view-full-post-btn">Read More<i class="fa fa-arrow-right"></i></span></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.yellowmarshmallow.co.uk/blog/3-hottest-trends-in-web-design-and-branding/">3 hottest trends in web design and branding</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.yellowmarshmallow.co.uk">Web Design Telford | Web Design Shropshire</a>.</p>
]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Over the years, web design has changed a lot. Early websites from the 90s now look like relics from a lost civilisation. There are many reasons for the change in web design; an understanding that simple messaging is key, rather than trying to stuff your homepage with as many calls to action as possible. A greater acceptance of scrolling, allowing the use of full-screen images. Smartphones becoming ubiquitous led to simplified designs that could easily be viewed on a desktop or mobile. The design of your website needs to evolve constantly in like with technological developments and aesthetic movements. </p>
<p>1. Don’t be imprisoned by grids<br />
 <br />
Web design naturally lends itself to grids and organising your layout in such a way keeps it looking simple, elegant, and easy to navigate. This has been the case for some time now and such designs are looking boring, corporate, and lazy. Recently there have been many different attempts to break out of the confines of grid-based design and to do something more interesting. Memphis Design is one such attempt that is becoming increasingly popular. It began in the 1980s primarily in furniture and interior design. Art déco, 1950s Kitsch, and pop art were the main inspirations behind Memphis Design. These design elements are now finding their way into web design characterised by irregular patterns and pastel colours. </p>
<p>2. Chatbots that are friendly and useful</p>
<p>Chatbots have quickly become an essential element to incorporate into your web design. In the past, these instant messaging systems all looked fairly uniform like pale imitations of Facebook Messenger. Now they have become an accepted and integral part of many websites, people are thinking more about their design. Bright colours not only draw attention to them but they also make them seem friendlier. More and more websites are also including a mascot to represent their chatbot to give a warmer feeling to the interaction. </p>
<p>3. Step out from the corner</p>
<p>The grid layout of old websites, and many current ones, lends itself to using geometric shapes, such as squares, rectangles and even triangles. These straight lines and sharp edges can create a sense of stability and professionalism. However, they are also beginning to feel cold and out-dated. There is increasingly a move towards using more fluid and organic shapes and lines. These design elements are asymmetrical but give users a more natural vibe. Incorporating natural design elements into your website can make it feel more friendly, comfortable, and accessible.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.yellowmarshmallow.co.uk/blog/3-hottest-trends-in-web-design-and-branding/">3 hottest trends in web design and branding</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.yellowmarshmallow.co.uk">Web Design Telford | Web Design Shropshire</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Why typography matters more than you realise</title>
		<link>https://www.yellowmarshmallow.co.uk/blog/why-typography-matters-more-than-you-realise/</link>
		<pubDate>Mon, 13 May 2019 10:38:47 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Lee Stewart]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Blog]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.yellowmarshmallow.co.uk/blog/why-typography-matters-more-than-you-realise/</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<p>When it comes to creating anything for your brand – a website, social media content, business stationery, advertising content – the written content matters greatly. It communicates your purpose, can<span class="view-full-post-btn">Read More<i class="fa fa-arrow-right"></i></span></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.yellowmarshmallow.co.uk/blog/why-typography-matters-more-than-you-realise/">Why typography matters more than you realise</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.yellowmarshmallow.co.uk">Web Design Telford | Web Design Shropshire</a>.</p>
]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>When it comes to creating anything for your brand – a website, social media content, business stationery, advertising content – the written content matters greatly. It communicates your purpose, can help you connect with your target audience, and can be a huge component of your brand identity.</p>
<p>But something that often gets overlooked is just how important typography can be in shaping your brand identity. With fonts, good text formatting can be a subtle but powerful design element, but bad fonts will stick out like a sore, visually unappealing thumb. Bad fonts even have the power to transcend notoriety amongst designers and become a pop-culture phenomenon. For instance, 2009’s ‘Avatar’ famously used the Microsoft Word pre-set font ‘Papyrus’ for its opening titles and the gimmicky typeset of Comic Sans has become a shorthand for laughably bad graphic design.</p>
<p>But aside from giving a wide berth to Microsoft WordArt and Wingdings, what are the principles of typography that can help elevate your brand image? </p>
<p>1)	Consistent styles </p>
<p>If you’ve ever flicked through magazines in a dentist waiting room, you may have picked up on how these publications have a limited, but carefully chosen, repertoire of fonts and text styles. They may have a font for headlines/key topics, the body text, and a secondary font for pull quotes (perhaps italicised or in bold for emphasis) – all of which work together to create an appealing page of text. </p>
<p>This is very much a question of quality over quantity; using a minimal amount of variation will always be more appealing than using a plethora of different fonts and styles. </p>
<p>2)	Clarity</p>
<p>The worst thing that any font can be is hard to read. After all, how aesthetically pleasing a typeset can be is subjective, but readability is key to good typography. Typically this means placing headlines/key information in larger text, breaking up copy with similarly bold subheadings, and making sure that the main body text is not too small.</p>
<p>Using san-serif fonts for the main copy, making sure text has sufficient tracking (spacing between letters), and ensuring the appropriate use of kerning are all elements of typography that can be used to help visitors to your site get all the information they need. </p>
<p>3)	Matching the rest of your aesthetic </p>
<p>Typography also needs to blend with the rest of the visual content. A website for a Saville Row tailor would simply look wrong if it used the same style of typography as a skate shop, for example. Of course, you can absolutely aim to break pre-existing moulds with your brand identity. But making sure that the text doesn’t look incongruent with photos and design assets on your website or social media content is another way that typography can really help strengthen your image. </p>
<p>When it comes to personalising your web design, your social media feeds, business stationery, or any other aspects of your brand image, we can help you create a consistent visual style to match your ideals and goals as a company.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.yellowmarshmallow.co.uk/blog/why-typography-matters-more-than-you-realise/">Why typography matters more than you realise</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.yellowmarshmallow.co.uk">Web Design Telford | Web Design Shropshire</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>How to make your website SEO Friendly</title>
		<link>https://www.yellowmarshmallow.co.uk/blog/how-to-make-your-website-seo-friendly/</link>
		<pubDate>Thu, 11 Apr 2019 08:26:39 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Lee Stewart]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Blog]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.yellowmarshmallow.co.uk/blog/how-to-make-your-website-seo-friendly/</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<p>Search Engine Optimization (SEO) has proved to be a tough topic for even some web designers. In the modern world of e-commerce, the success of a website depends on its<span class="view-full-post-btn">Read More<i class="fa fa-arrow-right"></i></span></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.yellowmarshmallow.co.uk/blog/how-to-make-your-website-seo-friendly/">How to make your website SEO Friendly</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.yellowmarshmallow.co.uk">Web Design Telford | Web Design Shropshire</a>.</p>
]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Search Engine Optimization (SEO) has proved to be a tough topic for even some web designers. In the modern world of e-commerce, the success of a website depends on its power to utilize SEO. Wondering how you to make your website SEO friendly? Here are guidelines to get you there.</p>
<p>Use of keywords</p>
<p>There are millions of business websites yours included, struggling to grab a share of the online market. Your ability to stand above others depends on your creativity. Proper utilization of keywords will rank your website higher in the search engines driving more traffic into the website. To establish relevant keywords related to your product or page, think of common words that clients can enter in the search engine. Try searching those words to find out the most searched terms. Have a related list of keywords and include them in your blog. </p>
<p>Create a website URL containing keywords</p>
<p>Having a URL link which includes brand keywords will make it easier for the search engine to find your website. When developing your web page, the web designer should optimize your web page through including keywords in the URL. Avoid using numbers and symbols when creating the URL and instead utilize keywords. For example, www.website.com/how-to-make-your-website-seo-friendly is better than www.website.com/5-guideline-to-make-your-web.</p>
<p>Quality of the content</p>
<p>The quality of the content that you post on your website determines its ability to comply with SEO standards. Low-quality content which fails to be indexed by search engines cannot display in search results. Publish high-quality content that answers the questions of visitors. You can also make your web friendly through avoiding posting duplicate content that may attract SEO penalty which will negatively impact your SEO ranking. </p>
<p>Use of images </p>
<p>If used well, pictures can help you to optimize your website. For example, instead of posting a picture describing it as image445.jpg, you can use a keyword to name it as logo.jpg. The strategy will help the image to appear in the search results. </p>
<p>Use of social media platforms</p>
<p>Although Google does not use social media in their ranking algorithm, you can benefit from proper social media management strategies. An example is when you link social media networks to your website facilitating your ability to share the website content to social media. The shared content increases the number of viewers and drives more traffic to your web page besides widening your brand exposure. </p>
<p>There are more ways of making your website SEO friendly in addition to those mentioned. You can contact a web designer to help you in the process of branding your web to make it SEO friendly.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.yellowmarshmallow.co.uk/blog/how-to-make-your-website-seo-friendly/">How to make your website SEO Friendly</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.yellowmarshmallow.co.uk">Web Design Telford | Web Design Shropshire</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Do you need branding on your business stationary?</title>
		<link>https://www.yellowmarshmallow.co.uk/blog/do-you-need-branding-on-your-business-stationary/</link>
		<pubDate>Fri, 08 Mar 2019 14:04:29 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Lee Stewart]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Blog]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.yellowmarshmallow.co.uk/blog/do-you-need-branding-on-your-business-stationary/</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<p>With modern printing technologies, you can get your logo and branding on pretty much anything. This opens up exciting opportunities to be creative with your branding and get as much<span class="view-full-post-btn">Read More<i class="fa fa-arrow-right"></i></span></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.yellowmarshmallow.co.uk/blog/do-you-need-branding-on-your-business-stationary/">Do you need branding on your business stationary?</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.yellowmarshmallow.co.uk">Web Design Telford | Web Design Shropshire</a>.</p>
]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>With modern printing technologies, you can get your logo and branding on pretty much anything. This opens up exciting opportunities to be creative with your branding and get as much exposure as possible. One thing that’s gaining popularity lately is branded stationary. But is this something your business actually needs?</p>
<p>To help you decide, we’ve put together the top 5 benefits it can bring your business. </p>
<p>1. It separates your business from the ordinary</p>
<p>Be honest now, when you think of stationary, what do you think? We’re guessing that the first thing that comes into your mind is the drab and boring pens and paper that we’re used to. After all, we’ve seen this and have interacted with it all of our lives. </p>
<p>But, if your customer sees your branded stationary, you’ll give them a break from the normal. This can be enough to spark interest and make them take note. It could even be enough to separate your business from the competition and make your audience think that you don’t do things the ordinary way. </p>
<p>2. It adds professionalism</p>
<p>Business stationery isn’t a new thing. People have been using it to create branded letterheads, envelopes and business cards for years. </p>
<p>There’s a clear and simple reason for this, it adds a letter of professionalism and trust to everything you provide. After all, if you got a letter addressed from your bank without any logos on it, would you trust it? </p>
<p>3. It lasts </p>
<p>With rapidly changing technology and ways to instantly access the interest, most marketing is done online. Although that can help expand your reach, there’s one problem with online marketing, it’s temporary. As soon as your customers click away, your advertisement is gone and they may never come back into contact with it. </p>
<p>On the flip side, branded stationary doesn’t disappear. It’ll last as long people as use it. </p>
<p>4. It gives your customers value</p>
<p>Having branded business stationary doesn’t necessarily mean printing your logo on the side of cheap, disposable pens that will end up being thrown away. </p>
<p>Instead, give them quality products that actually add value to your customer. If you give your customers something that they’ll actually want to use, they’re more likely to remember and engage with your brand. </p>
<p>5. It’s memorable marketing </p>
<p>One of the most important marketing rules is to be memorable and make a connection. </p>
<p>So, if you give away stationary with your branding on it, potential customers will be looking at your branding every time they pick it up. Which means you’re guaranteed that every single time someone uses your stationary, they’ll think of your company. </p>
<p>Think that branded business stationery is right for your company?</p>
<p>Trust the experts to give you a high-quality print that you can be proud of. Get in touch with our team today to find out more.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.yellowmarshmallow.co.uk/blog/do-you-need-branding-on-your-business-stationary/">Do you need branding on your business stationary?</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.yellowmarshmallow.co.uk">Web Design Telford | Web Design Shropshire</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Ensure your business gets the most from Facebook</title>
		<link>https://www.yellowmarshmallow.co.uk/blog/ensure-your-business-gets-the-most-from-facebook/</link>
		<pubDate>Fri, 08 Feb 2019 16:49:17 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Lee Stewart]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Blog]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.yellowmarshmallow.co.uk/blog/ensure-your-business-gets-the-most-from-facebook/</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<p>If you are a consumer-facing business, there is every reason to use Facebook. The world&#8217;s most popular social media site, with over two billion users, allows you to promote your<span class="view-full-post-btn">Read More<i class="fa fa-arrow-right"></i></span></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.yellowmarshmallow.co.uk/blog/ensure-your-business-gets-the-most-from-facebook/">Ensure your business gets the most from Facebook</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.yellowmarshmallow.co.uk">Web Design Telford | Web Design Shropshire</a>.</p>
]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>If you are a consumer-facing business, there is every reason to use Facebook. The world&#8217;s most popular social media site, with over two billion users, allows you to promote your business in a number of ways. </p>
<p>If you haven&#8217;t yet realised the potential of Facebook in your social media management plan, take a look at the strategies below which can help:</p>
<p>Painting a picture</p>
<p>While Facebook is the most popular social media site in the modern day, Instagram is among the fastest growing in recent times. One of the reasons for its popularity is an image-led design which puts the picture first. It is recognised that social media users respond more to images than text-based posts, so if you aren&#8217;t regularly posting engaging images, you could be missing a trick. It can be anything from a promotional flyer, to a product photo, snap of a happy customer, or images from an event attended by your company &#8211; keep your images coming thick and fast!</p>
<p>Ultra-targeted ads</p>
<p>One of the advantages which Facebook has over other online advertising platforms &#8211; Google Ads for example &#8211; is an ultra-targeted way of connecting with an audience. Not only can you choose the age, gender and location of the people who see your ad, but you can also narrow down your audience according to their interests. That means if you are a company which makes cupcakes, you can target those with a &#8216;like&#8217; for cupcakes! Or if you are a wallpaper manufacturer, you can reach those with an interest in interior design. It all adds up to a more efficient way of spending your online ad budget.</p>
<p>Become a &#8216;groupie&#8217; </p>
<p>Facebook offers many opportunities to target your local community or an interest-based community over a larger area. That&#8217;s because you can gain access to many groups which allow you to post about products and services. Be sure to only pick relevant groups, and beware of groups which disallow any kind of advertising. Although you should bear in mind, it can still be worthwhile engaging with Facebook groups even if you can&#8217;t advertise directly on them. Become a trusted source of advice for members of a group, and you could see a welcome knock-on effect for your business.</p>
<p>Those are a few Facebook business tips from us. Remember that a big part of social media success can come down to consistency, so try to formulate a social media plan which can give you structure over a few weeks or months.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.yellowmarshmallow.co.uk/blog/ensure-your-business-gets-the-most-from-facebook/">Ensure your business gets the most from Facebook</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.yellowmarshmallow.co.uk">Web Design Telford | Web Design Shropshire</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Why appearance is everything when it comes to your business brand</title>
		<link>https://www.yellowmarshmallow.co.uk/blog/why-appearance-is-everything-when-it-comes-to-your-business-brand/</link>
		<pubDate>Tue, 08 Jan 2019 09:31:33 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Lee Stewart]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Blog]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.yellowmarshmallow.co.uk/blog/why-appearance-is-everything-when-it-comes-to-your-business-brand/</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<p>You wouldn&#8217;t turn up to work sloppily dressed, so why would you allow your business brand to appear disorganised and messy? The reality is, appearance truly matters when it comes<span class="view-full-post-btn">Read More<i class="fa fa-arrow-right"></i></span></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.yellowmarshmallow.co.uk/blog/why-appearance-is-everything-when-it-comes-to-your-business-brand/">Why appearance is everything when it comes to your business brand</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.yellowmarshmallow.co.uk">Web Design Telford | Web Design Shropshire</a>.</p>
]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>You wouldn&#8217;t turn up to work sloppily dressed, so why would you allow your business brand to appear disorganised and messy? The reality is, appearance truly matters when it comes to creating a successful brand that customers and clients will continue to use and love. The services you provide might be fantastic, but they will mean nothing without the appropriate marketing techniques and unique website design; without them, your business will never flourish. Here are some key reasons why appearance shouldn&#8217;t be an afterthought when it comes to company branding: </p>
<p>1. It&#8217;s all about the consumer</p>
<p>With so many companies offering similar services on the market, it&#8217;s down to the consumer to choose which business is deserving of their time or money. Appearances have a great impact on this decision and a consumer will tend to go with a branding that they can resonate with and deem to be trustworthy. A company&#8217;s brand has to stand out on all platforms, including through social media and blog posts, all of which direct the consumer to the company website, which should be easy to navigate and aesthetically unique. A brand that appears half-finished or unprofessional is unlikely to appeal to any potential customers. </p>
<p>2. Aesthetics make your brand stand out</p>
<p>Not only can certain branding colours and design choices influence our <a href="https://www.yellowmarshmallow.co.uk/blog/why-the-psychology-of-colour-is-key-for-web-design/">psychology</a>, they can make your company more memorable among the vast amount of competition. Cohesive branding breeds loyalty with customers and iconic images, colours, or even font choice will make it easier for the consumer to recognise your brand and consistently use your services.   It&#8217;s a mistake to copy the design and marketing techniques from other companies, even if their branding is successful; you need to be creative and unique. Simple web design choices that improve the user experience and streamline their navigation through your website make all the difference; it&#8217;s small details like this that make you stand out. </p>
<p>3. It&#8217;s more than just skin deep</p>
<p>Excellent and well thought out branding design suggests that a company really understands its core values and the services that it aims to provide. A greater focus on branding design suggests to the consumer that you care about building a relationship with them, hoping to provide superior services instead of just setting up a business for monetary gain. </p>
<p>For an aesthetically stunning website that&#8217;s user-friendly, <a href="https://www.yellowmarshmallow.co.uk/website-designer-telford-shropshire/#contact">contact</a> a member of our team to see if our web design services are right for your business.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.yellowmarshmallow.co.uk/blog/why-appearance-is-everything-when-it-comes-to-your-business-brand/">Why appearance is everything when it comes to your business brand</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.yellowmarshmallow.co.uk">Web Design Telford | Web Design Shropshire</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>3 awesome reasons outsourcing your blog management makes sense</title>
		<link>https://www.yellowmarshmallow.co.uk/blog/3-awesome-reasons-outsourcing-your-blog-management-makes-sense/</link>
		<pubDate>Fri, 07 Dec 2018 15:46:20 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Lee Stewart]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Blog]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.yellowmarshmallow.co.uk/blog/3-awesome-reasons-outsourcing-your-blog-management-makes-sense/</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<p>Modern business has changed greatly in recent years to become increasingly digital. Consumers now use the internet to not only search for goods or services but to purchase them also.<span class="view-full-post-btn">Read More<i class="fa fa-arrow-right"></i></span></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.yellowmarshmallow.co.uk/blog/3-awesome-reasons-outsourcing-your-blog-management-makes-sense/">3 awesome reasons outsourcing your blog management makes sense</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.yellowmarshmallow.co.uk">Web Design Telford | Web Design Shropshire</a>.</p>
]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Modern business has changed greatly in recent years to become increasingly digital. Consumers now use the internet to not only search for goods or services but to purchase them also. A key part of engaging digitally with consumers for modern businesses is adding fresh content to their website regularly. This has been shown to not only build your brands authority with the public but also drive traffic to your website.</p>
<p>With this in mind, many businesses will happily set their own blog up to achieve this goal. However, this is not the best way to go about it! While having a regularly updated blog is key, it often makes sense to outsource the management of it to a professional marketing agency.</p>
<p>But why should you think about doing this?</p>
<p>Saves you lots of time</p>
<p>A useful and relevant business blog is great for driving more traffic to your site and helping to generate more leads. However, keeping it updated properly is not a quick process. By the time you have thought of what to write, actually written it and then posted the article up, it can eat into your working day. Multiply this by up to 4 or 5 blog posts per week and you can see where the issue lies in doing it yourself. Outsourcing all this means you get the blog articles you need but without it taking you away from your core work.</p>
<p>Access to top quality copywriters</p>
<p>Having a blog for your business only works if the content there is top-class. If you manage your own blog but are not a professional writer then this can be a problem. The chances are that you will end up with poorly written content that could actually harm your brand&#8217;s image. Using an external marketing agency avoids this by giving you access to the best writers around to craft your content.</p>
<p>Keeps your blog updated</p>
<p>Most businesses who try to manage their own blog soon find the intervals between new posts getting bigger and bigger. With core daily tasks to complete, there can simply be not enough time to write new content for it. The problem here is that this will look bad to customers who see it and harm your website&#8217;s search engine rankings. Outsourcing your blog management avoids this and means that you can rely on a steady stream of new content being produced each week.</p>
<p>Call Yellow Marshmallow today</p>
<p>If you would like to find out more about blog management then call us today on 01925 455 715. Our expert team of professional copywriters are waiting to deliver the content your blog requires. Our choice of blog management packages means you can select the best one for your needs and have total peace of mind that your blog is in good hands.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.yellowmarshmallow.co.uk/blog/3-awesome-reasons-outsourcing-your-blog-management-makes-sense/">3 awesome reasons outsourcing your blog management makes sense</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.yellowmarshmallow.co.uk">Web Design Telford | Web Design Shropshire</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>3 key benefits of social media management</title>
		<link>https://www.yellowmarshmallow.co.uk/blog/3-key-benefits-of-social-media-management/</link>
		<pubDate>Wed, 07 Nov 2018 10:48:01 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Lee Stewart]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Blog]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.yellowmarshmallow.co.uk/blog/3-key-benefits-of-social-media-management/</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<p>Social media has become a ubiquitous part of the way we communicate. As such, your online platform only stands to gain the more you engage with social media. A business<span class="view-full-post-btn">Read More<i class="fa fa-arrow-right"></i></span></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.yellowmarshmallow.co.uk/blog/3-key-benefits-of-social-media-management/">3 key benefits of social media management</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.yellowmarshmallow.co.uk">Web Design Telford | Web Design Shropshire</a>.</p>
]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Social media has become a ubiquitous part of the way we communicate. As such, your online platform only stands to gain the more you engage with social media. A business that does not have an up to date and active social media presence is often viewed as being &#8220;behind the times&#8221;. </p>
<p>Yellow Marshmallow offers a wide range of highly tailored <a href="https://www.yellowmarshmallow.co.uk/social-media-management/">social media management</a> services, designed to enhance your business. Here are just three of the many benefits that can hold for you. </p>
<h2>Proper scheduling</h2>
<p>Making the most of your social media profile depends on maximising the number of people who see and share what you&#8217;re posting. That means your content isn&#8217;t the only thing that matters &#8211; when you choose to post is also important. </p>
<p>There are a host of <a href="https://www.insight2marketing.com/blog/2016/04/18/11-benefits-of-scheduling-social-media-posts/">benefits of social media scheduling</a>. When you&#8217;re busy running your business, however, it can be difficult to take a timeout to make sure your Twitter post has gone live. With social media management, all of that is taken care of for you. </p>
<h2>Striking the right tone</h2>
<p>The importance of taking the time to interact with your customer base is a given. What is not so clear, however, is the right tone you should adopt. If you&#8217;re too casual you can seem unprofessional. If you&#8217;re too strict and dry, you can come off as cold and inhuman. Both of these are costly in their own way. </p>
<p>With social media management, you can be sure you understand the right <a href="https://www.bmmagazine.co.uk/marketing/social-media/the-right-tone-of-voice-for-your-social-media/">tone of voice</a> your social media profile should present. This varies depending on a number of factors &#8211; ranging from the type of business you operate to the spread of your customer demographics. To get it right, make sure you involve the <a href="https://www.yellowmarshmallow.co.uk/social-media-management/">specialists</a>.</p>
<h2>Saving money</h2>
<p>It sounds counter-intuitive for something you&#8217;re spending money on. But <a href="https://www.yellowmarshmallow.co.uk/social-media-management/">social media management</a> can save you a great deal of time. Cultivating content, responding to your followers, driving traffic &#8211; this is a full-time position in itself. One you likely don&#8217;t have time for, if you&#8217;re running a small business. </p>
<p>There are a number of different <a href="https://eclincher.com/blog/social-media-management-marketing-tools/">social media management tools</a> available. While they&#8217;re functional, however, they often require considerable time to understand how to operate them efficiently. Many of these tools aren&#8217;t free, either, so you&#8217;ll still have to pay to learn the software.</p>
<p>For even more reasons why <a href="https://www.yellowmarshmallow.co.uk/social-media-management/">social media management</a> matters, just ask Yellow Marshmallow.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.yellowmarshmallow.co.uk/blog/3-key-benefits-of-social-media-management/">3 key benefits of social media management</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.yellowmarshmallow.co.uk">Web Design Telford | Web Design Shropshire</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Website design; what your end users really want</title>
		<link>https://www.yellowmarshmallow.co.uk/blog/website-design-what-your-end-users-really-want/</link>
		<pubDate>Mon, 08 Oct 2018 14:11:04 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Lee Stewart]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Blog]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.yellowmarshmallow.co.uk/blog/website-design-what-your-end-users-really-want/</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<p>When designing a website there are a number of factors that you must consider, including SEO (search engine optimisation), logo design, content and overall layout. However, during this process, it<span class="view-full-post-btn">Read More<i class="fa fa-arrow-right"></i></span></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.yellowmarshmallow.co.uk/blog/website-design-what-your-end-users-really-want/">Website design; what your end users really want</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.yellowmarshmallow.co.uk">Web Design Telford | Web Design Shropshire</a>.</p>
]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>When designing a website there are a number of factors that you must consider, including SEO (search engine optimisation), logo design, content and overall layout. However, during this process, it is very easy to forget the most vital part of web design – the end user. Regardless of how good your SEO is, or whether your background colour matches your font, none of this matters if the website is difficult for the end user to use. At Yellow Marshmallow, our design team have expert knowledge in creating successful websites with a focus on end user experience and have created this short guide of helpful tips.</p>
<p>1.	Use engaging copy</p>
<p>If you want to convince your website traffic to become paying clients, then you must ensure that the written content of your page is engaging and persuasive. Don’t go for the hard sell, as this will put people off, but it is vital to use targeted and emotive language to help boost your conversion figures.</p>
<p>2.	Include calls to action</p>
<p>A great way to help increase your conversion rate, as well as making the experience easy for clients is to provide them with a clear call to action at the end of your content. This should give them specific directs, such as ‘take a look at’ or ‘buy now’, allowing them to act upon what they have just read.</p>
<p>3.	Include internal hyperlinks too</p>
<p>Within your website, it is essential that you include links to your other website pages, as this helps the website user to successfully and easily navigate your whole site without any confusion. This is also essential within any calls to action – an internal hyperlink is far more likely to get the end user to act due to the lack of effort it takes on their part.</p>
<p>4.	Have a contact page</p>
<p>Many potential customers will have questions about your products and services before buying, and as such is it essential to have clear contact details on your page. This is best done through an individual and specific contact web page rather than just having your details on the footer of the site. Equally, as different customers will want to contact you in different ways, you should include a variety of methods of contact, including email, telephone, and social media.</p>
<p>At Yellow Marshmallow, we pride ourselves on creating excellent web designs for our clients, as well as providing them with marketing and SEO services too. For more information, please contact us at https://www.yellowmarshmallow.co.uk/blog/#contact.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.yellowmarshmallow.co.uk/blog/website-design-what-your-end-users-really-want/">Website design; what your end users really want</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.yellowmarshmallow.co.uk">Web Design Telford | Web Design Shropshire</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Why the psychology of colour is key for web design</title>
		<link>https://www.yellowmarshmallow.co.uk/blog/why-the-psychology-of-colour-is-key-for-web-design/</link>
		<pubDate>Thu, 06 Sep 2018 09:10:10 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Lee Stewart]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Blog]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.yellowmarshmallow.co.uk/blog/why-the-psychology-of-colour-is-key-for-web-design/</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<p>Having a great website is key for any business. With clients increasingly finding companies through the internet, your website becomes their first real interaction with your branding and products. And<span class="view-full-post-btn">Read More<i class="fa fa-arrow-right"></i></span></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.yellowmarshmallow.co.uk/blog/why-the-psychology-of-colour-is-key-for-web-design/">Why the psychology of colour is key for web design</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.yellowmarshmallow.co.uk">Web Design Telford | Web Design Shropshire</a>.</p>
]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Having a great website is key for any business. With clients increasingly finding companies through the internet, your website becomes their first real interaction with your branding and products. And as well all know, first impressions really do count! </p>
<p>This means that your website design needs to be spot on. It needs to represent your company, show consistency with your branding and products, and provoke positive reactions in your end users, encouraging them the buy your products and services. Within this, the psychology of colour must be a key consideration for all people looking at their web design.</p>
<p>What is the psychology of colour?</p>
<p>The psychology of colour is a relatively new scientific understanding, with research on this phenomenon constantly being published. It states that humans have specific and innate reactions to different colours, with these colours provoking certain thoughts and feelings. Therefore, by understanding exactly what colours provoke what feelings in people, you can use colours to subtly influence emotions and associations. </p>
<p>How does this affect web design?</p>
<p>All websites use colours, whether as backgrounds, to highlight text, or even to differentiate certain parts of the webpage. By choosing colours that cause reactions and feelings that are in keeping with the content of your website, you can help to increase the likelihood that your end users will act in a certain way, whether that be to trust your brand (ideal for information pages), associate your products with ease and comfort (often used by eCommerce websites), or connect your services with motivation and change (commonly seen being used by consultancy companies). </p>
<p>So what is known so far?</p>
<p>As stated, the research on this phenomena is in its infancy, and there is not yet a definitive list of which colours cause which reactions – in fact, due to the complexity of the human mind, and the numbers of different experiences each person will have in their lifetime, it is unlikely that the psychology of colour will ever be truly objective, or completely black and white, if you will pardon the pun! However, since the psychology of colour is increasingly being used by marketing departments, publishers and designers, it is well worth ensuring that your website is keeping abreast of these developments, and using this knowledge efficiently and effectively.</p>
<p>At Yellow Marshmallow, we pride ourselves on offering a whole portfolio of web design, marking and branding solutions for your company. For more information about our services, or how we can help you, please contact us at https://www.yellowmarshmallow.co.uk/blog/#contact.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.yellowmarshmallow.co.uk/blog/why-the-psychology-of-colour-is-key-for-web-design/">Why the psychology of colour is key for web design</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.yellowmarshmallow.co.uk">Web Design Telford | Web Design Shropshire</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
